<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Virtual_Machine_Management_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Creating_a_Linux_virtual_machine" remap="TID_7476">
	<title>Creating a Linux Virtual Machine</title>
	<para>
		Create a new virtual machine and configure the required settings.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Creating Linux Virtual Machines</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guibutton>Virtual Machines</guibutton> tab.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guibutton>New VM</guibutton> button to open the <guilabel>New Virtual Machine</guilabel> window.
			</para>
			<figure id="new_vm-window-44">
				<title>The New Virtual Machine Window</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/7316.png" format="PNG" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select a Linux variant from the <guilabel>Operating System</guilabel> drop-down list.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter a <guilabel>Name</guilabel> for the virtual machine.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
		  <para>
		    Add storage to the virtual machine. <guibutton>Attach</guibutton> or <guibutton>Create</guibutton> a virtual disk under <guilabel>Instance Images</guilabel>.
		  </para>
		  <stepalternatives>
		    <step>
		      <para>
			Click <guibutton>Attach</guibutton> and select an existing virtual disk. 
		      </para>
		    </step>
		    <step>
		      <para>
			Click <guibutton>Create</guibutton> and enter a <guilabel>Size(GB)</guilabel> and <guilabel>Alias</guilabel> for a new virtual disk. You can accept the default settings for all other fields, or change them if required. See <xref linkend="Add_Virtual_Disk_dialogue_entries" /> for more details on the fields for all disk types.
		      </para>
		    </step>
		  </stepalternatives>
		</step>
		<step>
		  <para>
		    Connect the virtual machine to the network. Add a network interface by selecting a vNIC profile from the <guilabel>nic1</guilabel> drop-down list at the bottom of the <guilabel>General</guilabel> tab.
		  </para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Specify the virtual machine's <guilabel>Memory Size</guilabel> on the <guilabel>System</guilabel> tab.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Choose the <guilabel>First Device</guilabel> that the virtual machine will boot from on the <guilabel>Boot Options</guilabel> tab.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				You can accept the default settings for all other fields, or change them if required. For more details on all fields in the <guilabel>New Virtual Machine</guilabel> window, see <xref linkend="sect-Explanation_of_Settings_in_the_New_Virtual_Machine_and_Edit_Virtual_Machine_Windows" />.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		The new virtual machine is created and displays in the list of virtual machines with a status of <literal>Down</literal>. Before you can use this virtual machine, you must install an operating system and register with the Content Delivery Network.
	</para>
</section>