<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Virtual_Machine_Management_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Creating_a_virtual_machine_from_a_snapshot" remap="TID_10393">
	<title>Creating a Virtual Machine from a Snapshot</title>
	<para>
		You have created a snapshot from a virtual machine. Now you can use that snapshot to create another virtual machine.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Creating a virtual machine from a snapshot</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Virtual Machines</guilabel> tab and select a virtual machine.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Snapshots</guilabel> tab in the details pane to list the available snapshots.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select a snapshot in the list displayed and click <guibutton>Clone</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Description</guilabel> for the virtual machine.
			</para>
			<figure id="clone_vm_from_snapshot">
				<title>Clone a Virtual Machine from a Snapshot</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/6581.png" format="PNG" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		After a short time, the cloned virtual machine appears in the <guilabel>Virtual Machines</guilabel> tab in the navigation pane with a status of <literal>Image Locked</literal>. The virtual machine will remain in this state until Red Hat Virtualization completes the creation of the virtual machine. A virtual machine with a preallocated 20 GB hard drive takes about fifteen minutes to create. Sparsely-allocated virtual disks take less time to create than do preallocated virtual disks.
	</para>
	<para>
		When the virtual machine is ready to use, its status changes from <literal>Image Locked</literal> to <literal>Down</literal> in the <guilabel>Virtual Machines</guilabel> tab in the navigation pane.
	</para>
</section>

