<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Virtual_Machine_Management_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Data_center_cluster_entities" remap="TID_7909">
	<title>Managing System Permissions for a Virtual Machine</title>
	<para>
		As the <guilabel>SuperUser</guilabel>, the system administrator manages all aspects of the Administration Portal. More specific administrative roles can be assigned to other users. These restricted administrator roles are useful for granting a user administrative privileges that limit them to a specific resource. For example, a <guilabel>DataCenterAdmin</guilabel> role has administrator privileges only for the assigned data center with the exception of the storage for that data center, and a <guilabel>ClusterAdmin</guilabel> has administrator privileges only for the assigned cluster.
	</para>
	<para>
		A <guilabel>UserVmManager</guilabel> is a system administration role for virtual machines in a data center. This role can be applied to specific virtual machines, to a data center, or to the whole virtualized environment; this is useful to allow different users to manage certain virtual resources.
	</para>
	<para>
		The user virtual machine administrator role permits the following actions: 
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Create, edit, and remove virtual machines.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Run, suspend, shutdown, and stop virtual machines.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
	<note>
		<para>
			You can only assign roles and permissions to existing users.
		</para>
	</note>
	<para>
		Many end users are concerned solely with the virtual machine resources of the virtualized environment. As a result, Red Hat Virtualization provides several user roles which enable the user to manage virtual machines specifically, but not other resources in the data center.
	</para>
</section>

