<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Virtual_Machine_Management_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Exporting_individual_virtual_machines_to_the_export_domain" remap="TID_7515">
	<title>Exporting a Virtual Machine to the Export Domain</title>
	<para>
		Export a virtual machine to the export domain so that it can be imported into a different data center. Before you begin, the export domain must be attached to the data center that contains the virtual machine to be exported. 
	</para>
	<warning>
		<para>
			The virtual machine must be shut down before being exported. 
		</para>
	</warning>
	<procedure>
		<title>Exporting a Virtual Machine to the Export Domain</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Virtual Machines</guilabel> tab and select a virtual machine.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Export</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Optionally select the following check boxes: 
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Force Override</guilabel>: overrides existing images of the virtual machine on the export domain.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Collapse Snapshots</guilabel>: creates a single export volume per disk. This option removes snapshot restore points and includes the template in a template-based virtual machine, and removes any dependencies a virtual machine has on a template. For a virtual machine that is dependent on a template, either select this option, export the template with the virtual machine, or make sure the template exists in the destination data center.
						</para>
						<note>
							<para>
								When you create a virtual machine from a template, two storage allocation options are available under <menuchoice><guimenu>New Virtual Machine</guimenu><guisubmenu>Resource Allocation</guisubmenu><guimenuitem>Storage Allocation</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
							</para>
							<para>
								<itemizedlist>
									<listitem>
										<para>
											If <guilabel>Clone</guilabel> was selected, the virtual machine is not dependent on the template. The template does not have to exist in the destination data center.
										</para>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para>
											If <guilabel>Thin</guilabel> was selected, the virtual machine is dependent on the template, so the template must exist in the destination data center or be exported with the virtual machine. Alternatively, select the <guilabel>Collapse Snapshots</guilabel> check box to collapse the template disk and virtual machine disk into a single disk.
										</para>
									</listitem>
								</itemizedlist>
							</para>
							<para>
								To check which option was selected, select a virtual machine and click the <guilabel>General</guilabel> tab in the details pane.
							</para>
						</note>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		The export of the virtual machine begins. The virtual machine displays in the <guilabel>Virtual Machines</guilabel> results list with an <literal>Image Locked</literal> status while it is exported. Depending on the size of your virtual machine hard disk images, and your storage hardware, this can take up to an hour. Use the <guilabel>Events</guilabel> tab to view the progress. When complete, the virtual machine has been exported to the export domain and displays on the <guilabel>VM Import</guilabel> tab of the export domain's details pane.
	</para>
</section>
