<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Virtual_Machine_Management_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Manually_Associating_console.vv_Files_with_Remote_Viewer" remap="TID_30447">
	<title>Manually Associating console.vv Files with Remote Viewer</title>
	<para>
		If you are prompted to download a <filename>console.vv</filename> file when attempting to open a console to a virtual machine using the native client console option, and Remote Viewer is already installed, then you can manually associate <filename>console.vv</filename> files with Remote Viewer so that Remote Viewer can automatically use those files to open consoles.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Manually Associating console.vv Files with Remote Viewer</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Start the virtual machine.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Open the <guilabel>Console Options</guilabel> window.
			</para>
			<stepalternatives>
				<step>
					<para>
						In the Administration Portal, right-click the virtual machine and click <guilabel>Console Options</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						In the User Portal, click the <guilabel>Edit Console Options</guilabel> button.
					</para>
				</step>
			</stepalternatives>
			<figure>
				<title>The User Portal Edit Console Options Button</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/6145.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Change the console invocation method to <guilabel>Native client</guilabel> and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Attempt to open a console to the virtual machine, then click <guibutton>Save</guibutton> when prompted to open or save the <filename>console.vv</filename> file.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to the location on your local machine where you saved the file.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Double-click the <filename>console.vv</filename> file and select <guibutton>Select a program from a list of installed programs</guibutton> when prompted.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the <guilabel>Open with</guilabel> window, select <guibutton>Always use the selected program to open this kind of file</guibutton> and click the <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> button.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to the <filename>C:\Users\<replaceable>[user name]</replaceable>\AppData\Local\virt-viewer\bin</filename> directory and select <filename>remote-viewer.exe</filename>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Open</guibutton> and then click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		When you use the native client console invocation option to open a console to a virtual machine, Remote Viewer will automatically use the <filename>console.vv</filename> file that the Red Hat Virtualization Manager provides to open a console to that virtual machine without prompting you to select the application to use.
	</para>
</section>

