<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Virtual_Machine_Management_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Template_User_Roles_Explained" remap="TID_11150">
	<title>Template User Roles Explained</title>
	<para>
		The table below describes the user roles and privileges applicable to using and administrating templates in the User Portal.
	</para>
	<table id="Template_User_Roles">
		<title>Red Hat Virtualization Template User Roles</title>
		<tgroup cols="3">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Role
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Privileges
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Notes
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						TemplateCreator
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can create, edit, manage and remove virtual machine templates within assigned resources.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						The <guilabel>TemplateCreator</guilabel> role is not applied to a specific template; apply this role to a user for the whole environment with the <guilabel>Configure</guilabel> window. Alternatively apply this role for specific data centers, clusters, or storage domains.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						TemplateOwner
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can edit and delete the template, assign and manage user permissions for the template.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						The <guilabel>TemplateOwner</guilabel> role is automatically assigned to the user who creates a template. Other users who do not have <guilabel>TemplateOwner</guilabel> permissions on a template cannot view or use the template.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						UserTemplateBasedVm
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can use the template to create virtual machines.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Cannot edit template properties.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						VnicProfileUser
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Logical network and network interface user for templates.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						If the <guilabel>Allow all users to use this Network</guilabel> option was selected when a logical network is created, <guilabel>VnicProfileUser</guilabel> permissions are assigned to all users for the logical network. Users can then attach or detach template network interfaces to or from the logical network.
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
</section>

