<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Virtual_Machine_Management_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Virtual_Machine_Initial_Run_settings_explained" remap="TID_10742">
	<title>Virtual Machine Initial Run Settings Explained</title>
	<para>
		The following table details the options available on the <guilabel>Initial Run</guilabel> tab of the <guilabel>New Virtual Machine</guilabel> and <guilabel>Edit Virtual Machine</guilabel> windows. The settings in this table are only visible if the <guilabel>Use Cloud-Init/Sysprep</guilabel> check box is selected, and certain options are only visible when either a Linux-based or Windows-based option has been selected in the <guilabel>Operating System</guilabel> list in the <guilabel>General</guilabel> tab, as outlined below.
	</para>
	<table frame="all" id="New_VMs_Initial_Run-227">
		<title>Virtual Machine: Initial Run Settings</title>
		<tgroup align="left" cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
			<colspec colname="c1" colwidth="30%" />
			<colspec colname="c2" colwidth="20%" />
			<colspec colname="c2" colwidth="50%" />
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Field Name
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Operating System
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Description
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Use Cloud-Init/Sysprep</guilabel>
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Linux, Windows
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							This check box toggles whether Cloud-Init or Sysprep will be used to initialize the virtual machine.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>VM Hostname</guilabel>
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Linux, Windows
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The host name of the virtual machine.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Domain</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Windows
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The Active Directory domain to which the virtual machine belongs.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Organization Name</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Windows
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The name of the organization to which the virtual machine belongs. This option corresponds to the text field for setting the organization name displayed when a machine running Windows is started for the first time.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Active Directory OU</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Windows
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The organizational unit in the Active Directory domain to which the virtual machine belongs.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Configure Time Zone</guilabel>
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Linux, Windows
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The time zone for the virtual machine. Select this check box and select a time zone from the <guilabel>Time Zone</guilabel> list.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Admin Password</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Windows
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The administrative user password for the virtual machine. Click the disclosure arrow to display the settings for this option.
						</para>
						<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para> 
									<guilabel>Use already configured password</guilabel>: This check box is automatically selected after you specify an initial administrative user password. You must clear this check box to enable the <guilabel>Admin Password</guilabel> and <guilabel>Verify Admin Password</guilabel> fields and specify a new password.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para> 
									<guilabel>Admin Password</guilabel>: The administrative user password for the virtual machine. Enter the password in this text field and the <guilabel>Verify Admin Password</guilabel> text field to verify the password.
								</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Authentication</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Linux
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The authentication details for the virtual machine. Click the disclosure arrow to display the settings for this option. 
							<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para> 
										<guilabel>Use already configured password</guilabel>: This check box is automatically selected after you specify an initial root password. You must clear this check box to enable the <guilabel>Password</guilabel> and <guilabel>Verify Password</guilabel> fields and specify a new password.
									</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para> 
										<guilabel>Password</guilabel>: The root password for the virtual machine. Enter the password in this text field and the <guilabel>Verify Password</guilabel> text field to verify the password.
									</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para> 
										<guilabel>SSH Authorized Keys</guilabel>: <acronym>SSH</acronym> keys to be added to the authorized keys file of the virtual machine. You can specify multiple <acronym>SSH</acronym> keys by entering each <acronym>SSH</acronym> key on a new line.
									</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para> 
										<guilabel>Regenerate SSH Keys</guilabel>: Regenerates <acronym>SSH</acronym> keys for the virtual machine.
									</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist>
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Custom Locale</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Windows
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Custom locale options for the virtual machine. Locales must be in a format such as <literal>en-US</literal>. Click the disclosure arrow to display the settings for this option.
						</para>
						<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para> 
									<guilabel>Input Locale</guilabel>: The locale for user input.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para> 
									<guilabel>UI Language</guilabel>: The language used for user interface elements such as buttons and menus.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para> 
									<guilabel>System Locale</guilabel>: The locale for the overall system.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para> 
									<guilabel>User Locale</guilabel>: The locale for users.
								</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Networks</guilabel>
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Linux
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Network-related settings for the virtual machine. Click the disclosure arrow to display the settings for this option.
						</para>
						<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para> 
									<guilabel>DNS Servers</guilabel>: The <acronym>DNS</acronym> servers to be used by the virtual machine.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para> 
									<guilabel>DNS Search Domains</guilabel>: The <acronym>DNS</acronym> search domains to be used by the virtual machine.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para> 
									<guilabel>Network</guilabel>: Configures network interfaces for the virtual machine. Select this check box and click <guilabel>+</guilabel> or <guilabel>-</guilabel> to add or remove network interfaces to or from the virtual machine. When you click <guilabel>+</guilabel>, a set of fields becomes visible that can specify whether to use <acronym>DHCP</acronym>, and configure an <acronym>IP</acronym> address, netmask, and gateway, and specify whether the network interface will start on boot.
								</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Custom Script</guilabel>
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Linux
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Custom scripts that will be run on the virtual machine when it starts. The scripts entered in this field are custom <acronym>YAML</acronym> sections that are added to those produced by the Manager, and allow you to automate tasks such as creating users and files, configuring <application>yum</application> repositories and running commands. For more information on the format of scripts that can be entered in this field, see the <ulink url="http://cloudinit.readthedocs.org/en/latest/topics/examples.html#yaml-examples">Custom Script</ulink> documentation.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Sysprep</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Windows
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							A custom Sysprep definition. The definition must be in the format of a complete unattended installation answer file. You can copy and paste the default answer files in the <filename>/usr/share/ovirt-engine/conf/sysprep/</filename> directory on the machine on which the Red Hat Virtualization Manager is installed and alter the fields as required.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
</section>

