<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Cockpit_UI_Plugin">
  <title>Accessing Cockpit from the Administration Portal</title>
  <para>
    The Cockpit UI plug-in is an optional feature that can be installed in Red Hat Virtualization environments. The plug-in provides access to the Cockpit user interface, used for monitoring and administering host resources, through the Administration Portal. When a host with Cockpit installed is selected, the <guilabel>Cockpit</guilabel> sub-tab shows the Cockpit user interface directly in the details pane in the Administration Portal. Alternatively, the <guibutton>Cockpit</guibutton> button in the main <guilabel>Hosts</guilabel> menu opens the Cockpit user interface in a new browser tab. 
  </para>
  <para>
    The Cockpit user interface is available by default on Red Hat Virtualization Host (RHVH). It is currently not supported on Red Hat Enterprise Linux hosts. <!--At least until BZ#1346835 is released -->
  </para>
  <procedure>
    <title>Accessing Cockpit from the Administration Portal</title>
    <step>
      <para>
        Install the Cockpit UI plug-in on the Manager machine:
      </para>
      <screen># yum install cockpit-ovirt-uiplugin</screen>
    </step>
    <step>
      <para>
        Restart the <systemitem>ovirt-engine</systemitem> service:
      </para>
      <screen># systemctl restart ovirt-engine.service</screen>
    </step>
    <step>
      <para>
        In the Administration Portal, click the <guilabel>Hosts</guilabel> tab and select a host. 
      </para>
    </step>
    <step>
      <para>
        Open the Cockpit user interface in a new tab, or view it directly through the Administration Portal: 
      </para>
      <stepalternatives>
        <step>
          <para>
            Right-click the host and select <guibutton>Cockpit</guibutton> to open the Cockpit user interface in a new browser tab.
          </para>
        </step>
        <step>
          <para>
            Click the <guilabel>Cockpit</guilabel> sub-tab to view the Cockpit user interface in the details pane of the <guilabel>Hosts</guilabel> tab.
          </para>
          <note>
            <para>
              If Cockpit is not available on the selected host, the Cockpit sub-tab shows basic troubleshooting steps.
            </para>
          </note>
        </step>
      </stepalternatives>
    </step>
  </procedure>
</section>