<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Adding_Satellite_for_Host_Provisioning" remap="TID_30108">
	<title>Adding a Red Hat Satellite Instance for Host Provisioning</title>
	<para>
		Add a Satellite instance for host provisioning to the Red Hat Virtualization Manager. Red Hat Virtualization 4.0 is supported with Red Hat Satellite 6.1. 
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Adding a Satellite Instance for Host Provisioning</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select the <guilabel>External Providers</guilabel> entry in the tree pane.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Add</guibutton> to open the <guilabel>Add Provider</guilabel> window.
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>The Add Provider Window</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/7286.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject> 
						<phrase>The Add Provider Window</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter a <guilabel>Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Description</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From the <guilabel>Type</guilabel> list, ensure that <guilabel>Foreman/Satellite</guilabel> is selected.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter the <acronym>URL</acronym> or fully qualified domain name of the machine on which the Satellite instance is installed in the <guilabel>Provider URL</guilabel> text field. You do not need to specify a port number.
			</para>
                        <important>
                            <para>
                                IP addresses cannot be used to add a Satellite instance. 
                                </para>
                        </important>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter the <guilabel>Username</guilabel> and <guilabel>Password</guilabel> for the Satellite instance. You must use the same user name and password as you would use to log in to the Satellite provisioning portal.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Test the credentials:
			</para>
			<substeps>
				<step>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Test</guilabel> to test whether you can authenticate successfully with the Satellite instance using the provided credentials.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						If the Satellite instance uses <acronym>SSL</acronym>, the <guilabel>Import provider certificates</guilabel> window opens; click <guilabel>OK</guilabel> to import the certificate that the Satellite instance provides.
					</para>
					<important>
						<para>
							You must import the certificate that the Satellite instance provides to ensure the Manager can communicate with the instance.
						</para>
					</important>
				</step>
			</substeps>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		You have added the Satellite instance to the Red Hat Virtualization Manager, and can work with the hosts it provides.
	</para>
</section>
