<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Adding_Red_Hat_Storage_Nodes" remap="TID_30634">
	<title>Adding Red Hat Gluster Storage Nodes</title>
	<para>
		Add Red Hat Gluster Storage nodes to Gluster-enabled clusters and incorporate GlusterFS volumes and bricks into your Red Hat Virtualization environment.
	</para>
	<para>
		This procedure presumes that you have a Gluster-enabled cluster of the appropriate <guilabel>Compatibility Version</guilabel> and a Red Hat Gluster Storage node already set up. For information on setting up a Red Hat Gluster Storage node, see the <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Storage/3.1/html/Installation_Guide/chap-Installing_Red_Hat_Storage.html">Red Hat Gluster Storage Installation Guide</ulink>. For more information on the compatibility matrix, see the <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/articles/2356261">Red Hat Gluster Storage Version Compatibility and Support</ulink>.
	</para> 
	<!--note>
		<para>
			Red Hat Gluster Storage does not currently support cluster in version 3.4 and later. The <guilabel>Compatibility Version</guilabel> of the cluster must be set to version 3.1, 3.2, or 3.3.
		</para>
	</note-->
	<procedure>
		<title>Adding a Red Hat Gluster Storage Node</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Hosts</guilabel> resource tab to list the hosts in the results list.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>New</guibutton> to open the <guilabel>New Host</guilabel> window.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Use the drop-down menus to select the <guilabel>Data Center</guilabel> and <guilabel>Host Cluster</guilabel> for the Red Hat Gluster Storage node.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter the <guilabel>Name</guilabel>, <guilabel>Address</guilabel>, and <guilabel>SSH Port</guilabel> of the Red Hat Gluster Storage node.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select an authentication method to use with the Red Hat Gluster Storage node.
			</para>
			<stepalternatives>
				<step>
					<para>
						Enter the root user's password to use password authentication.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Copy the key displayed in the <guilabel>SSH PublicKey</guilabel> field to <filename>/root/.ssh/authorized_keys</filename> on the Red Hat Gluster Storage node to use public key authentication.
					</para>
				</step>
			</stepalternatives>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to add the node and close the window.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		You have added a Red Hat Gluster Storage node to your Red Hat Virtualization environment. You can now use the volume and brick resources of the node in your environment.
	</para>
</section>



