<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Administrator_Roles_Explained" remap="TID_11325">
	<title>Administrator Roles Explained</title>
	<para>
		The table below describes basic administrator roles which confer permissions to access and configure resources in the Administration Portal.
	</para>
	<table id="Admin_Roles_Basic">
		<title>Red Hat Virtualization System Administrator Roles - Basic</title>
		<tgroup cols="3">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Role
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Privileges
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Notes
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						SuperUser
					</entry>
					<entry>
						System Administrator of the Red Hat Virtualization environment.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Has full permissions across all objects and levels, can manage all objects across all data centers.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						ClusterAdmin
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Cluster Administrator.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Possesses administrative permissions for all objects underneath a specific cluster.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						DataCenterAdmin
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Data Center Administrator.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Possesses administrative permissions for all objects underneath a specific data center except for storage.
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
	<important>
		<para>
			Do not use the administrative user for the directory server as the Red Hat Virtualization administrative user. Create a user in the directory server specifically for use as the Red Hat Virtualization administrative user.
		</para>
	</important>
	<para>
		The table below describes advanced administrator roles which allow you to do more fine tuning of permissions for resources in the Administration Portal.
	</para>
	<table id="Admin_Roles_Advanced">
		<title>Red Hat Virtualization System Administrator Roles - Advanced</title>
		<tgroup cols="3">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Role
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Privileges
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Notes
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						TemplateAdmin
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Administrator of a virtual machine template.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can create, delete, and configure the storage domains and network details of templates, and move templates between domains.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						StorageAdmin
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Storage Administrator.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can create, delete, configure, and manage an assigned storage domain.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						HostAdmin
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Host Administrator.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can attach, remove, configure, and manage a specific host.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						NetworkAdmin
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Network Administrator.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can configure and manage the network of a particular data center or cluster. A network administrator of a data center or cluster inherits network permissions for virtual pools within the cluster.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						VmPoolAdmin
					</entry>
					<entry>
						System Administrator of a virtual pool.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can create, delete, and configure a virtual pool; assign and remove virtual pool users; and perform basic operations on a virtual machine in the pool.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						GlusterAdmin
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Gluster Storage Administrator.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can create, delete, configure, and manage Gluster storage volumes.
					</entry>
				</row>
                                <row>
					<entry>
						VmImporterExporter
					</entry>
					<entry>
                                                Import and export Administrator of a virtual machine.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can import and export virtual machines. Able to view all virtual machines and templates exported by other users.
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
</section>

