<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Bonding_Logic_in_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization" remap="TID_22487">
	<title>Bonding Logic in Red Hat Virtualization</title>
	<para>
		The Red Hat Virtualization Manager Administration Portal allows you to create bond devices using a graphical interface. There are several distinct bond creation scenarios, each with its own logic.
	</para>
	<para>
		Two factors that affect bonding logic are:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Are either of the devices already carrying logical networks?
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Are the devices carrying compatible logical networks?
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<table>
		<title>Bonding Scenarios and Their Results</title>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Bonding Scenario
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Result
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							NIC + NIC
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Create New Bond</guilabel> window is displayed, and you can configure a new bond device.
						</para>
						<para>
							If the network interfaces carry incompatible logical networks, the bonding operation fails until you detach incompatible logical networks from the devices forming your new bond.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							NIC + Bond
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The NIC is added to the bond device. Logical networks carried by the NIC and the bond are all added to the resultant bond device if they are compatible.
						</para>
						<para>
							If the bond devices carry incompatible logical networks, the bonding operation fails until you detach incompatible logical networks from the devices forming your new bond.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Bond + Bond
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							If the bond devices are not attached to logical networks, or are attached to compatible logical networks, a new bond device is created. It contains all of the network interfaces, and carries all logical networks, of the component bond devices. The <guilabel>Create New Bond</guilabel> window is displayed, allowing you to configure your new bond.
						</para>
						<para>
							If the bond devices carry incompatible logical networks, the bonding operation fails until you detach incompatible logical networks from the devices forming your new bond.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
</section>

