<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Changing_the_password_for_admininternal_using_jdbc">
 <title>Changing the Password for the Internal Administrative User</title>
	<para>
		To reset the password of the internal administrative user (<literal>admin@internal</literal>), use the <command>ovirt-aaa-jdbc-tool</command> tool. You do not need to restart the <command>ovirt-engine</command> service for the password change to take effect.
	</para>
   <para>By default, the password policy for user accounts on the internal domain has the following restrictions:
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
       A minimum of 6 characters.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>
      Three previous passwords used cannot be set again during the password change.
     </para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
	 For more information on the password policy and other default settings, run <command>ovirt-aaa-jdbc-tool settings show</command>.
 </para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Resetting the Password for the Internal Administrative User</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Log in to the machine on which the Red Hat Virtualization Manager is installed.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				To change the password in interactive mode, run the following command. You must set a value for <command>--password-valid-to</command>, otherwise the password expiry time defaults to the current time. The date format is <literal>yyyy-MM-dd HH:mm:ssX</literal>. In this example, <literal>Z</literal> stands for UTC time. For more options, run <command>ovirt-aaa-jdbc-tool user password-reset --help</command>.
				<screen># ovirt-aaa-jdbc-tool user password-reset <literal>admin</literal> --password-valid-to=<replaceable>"2025-08-01 12:00:00Z"</replaceable></screen>
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
</section>

