<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Creating_a_new_logical_network_in_a_data_center_or_cluster" remap="TID_7329">
	<title>Creating a New Logical Network in a Data Center or Cluster</title>
	<para>
		Create a logical network and define its use in a data center, or in clusters in a data center.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Creating a New Logical Network in a Data Center or Cluster</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Data Centers</guilabel> or <guilabel>Clusters</guilabel> resource tabs, and select a data center or cluster in the results list.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Logical Networks</guilabel> tab of the details pane to list the existing logical networks.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<stepalternatives>
				<step>
					<para>
						From the <guilabel>Data Centers</guilabel> details pane, click <guibutton>New</guibutton> to open the <guilabel>New Logical Network</guilabel> window.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						From the <guilabel>Clusters</guilabel> details pane, click <guibutton>Add Network</guibutton> to open the <guilabel>New Logical Network</guilabel> window.
					</para>
				</step>
			</stepalternatives>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter a <guilabel>Name</guilabel>, <guilabel>Description</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Comment</guilabel> for the logical network.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Optionally select the <guilabel>Create on external provider</guilabel> check box. Select the <guilabel>External Provider</guilabel> from the drop-down list and provide the IP address of the <guilabel>Physical Network</guilabel>. The <guilabel>External Provider</guilabel> drop-down list will not list any external providers in read-only mode.
			</para>
			<para>
				If <guilabel>Create on external provider</guilabel> is selected, the <guilabel>Network Label</guilabel>, <guilabel>VM Network</guilabel>, and <guilabel>MTU</guilabel> options are disabled.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter a new label or select an existing label for the logical network in the <guilabel>Network Label</guilabel> text field.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Optionally enable <guilabel>Enable VLAN tagging</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Optionally disable <guilabel>VM Network</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Set the <guilabel>MTU</guilabel> value to <guilabel>Default (1500)</guilabel> or <guilabel>Custom</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From the <guilabel>Cluster</guilabel> tab, select the clusters to which the network will be assigned. You can also specify whether the logical network will be a required network.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				If <guilabel>Create on external provider</guilabel> is selected, the <guilabel>Subnet</guilabel> tab will be visible. From the <guilabel>Subnet</guilabel> tab, select the <guilabel>Create subnet</guilabel> and enter a <guilabel>Name</guilabel>, <guilabel>CIDR</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Gateway</guilabel> address, and select an <guilabel>IP Version</guilabel> for the subnet that the logical network will provide. You can also add DNS servers as required.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From the <guilabel>vNIC Profiles</guilabel> tab, add vNIC profiles to the logical network as required.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guilabel>OK</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		You have defined a logical network as a resource required by a cluster or clusters in the data center. If you entered a label for the logical network, it will be automatically added to all host network interfaces with that label.
	</para>
	<note>
		<para>
			When creating a new logical network or making changes to an existing logical network that is used as a display network, any running virtual machines that use that network must be rebooted before the network becomes available or the changes are applied.
		</para>
	</note>
</section>
