<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Creating_a_desktop_pool" remap="TID_7591">
	<title>Creating a Virtual Machine Pool</title>
	<para>
		You can create a virtual machine pool that contains multiple virtual machines that have been created based on a common template.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Creating a Virtual Machine Pool</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Pools</guilabel> tab.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guibutton>New</guibutton> button to open the <guilabel>New Pool</guilabel> window.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
					<para>
						Use the drop down-list to select the <guilabel>Cluster</guilabel> or use the selected default.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Use the <guilabel>Template</guilabel> drop-down menu to select the required template and version or use the selected default. A template provides standard settings for all the virtual machines in the pool.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Use the <guilabel>Operating System</guilabel> drop-down list to select an <guilabel>Operating System</guilabel> or use the default provided by the template.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Use the <guilabel>Optimized for</guilabel> drop-down list to optimize virtual machines for either <guilabel>Desktop</guilabel> use or <guilabel>Server</guilabel> use.
					</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter a <guilabel>Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Description</guilabel>, any <guilabel>Comments</guilabel>, and the <guilabel>Number of VMs</guilabel> for the pool.
			</para>
		</step>
                <step>
			<para>
				Enter the number of virtual machines to be prestarted in the <guilabel>Prestarted VMs</guilabel> field.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select the <guilabel>Maximum number of VMs per user</guilabel> that a single user is allowed to run in a session. The minimum is one.
			</para>
		</step>
                <step> 
                    <para> 
                        Select the <guilabel>Delete Protection</guilabel> check box to enable delete protection. 
                    </para> 
                </step> 
		<step>
			<para>
				Optionally, click the <guilabel>Show Advanced Options</guilabel> button and perform the following steps:
			</para>
			<substeps>
                                <step>
					<para>
						Click the <guilabel>Type</guilabel> tab and select a <guilabel>Pool Type</guilabel>:
					</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para> 
								<guilabel>Manual</guilabel> - The administrator is responsible for explicitly returning the virtual machine to the pool. The virtual machine reverts to the original base image after the administrator returns it to the pool.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para> 
								<guilabel>Automatic</guilabel> - When the virtual machine is shut down, it automatically reverts to its base image and is returned to the virtual machine pool.
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Select the <guilabel>Console</guilabel> tab. At the bottom of the tab window, select the <guilabel>Override SPICE Proxy</guilabel> check box to enable the <guilabel>Overridden SPICE proxy address</guilabel> text field. Specify the address of a <acronym>SPICE</acronym> proxy to override the global <acronym>SPICE</acronym> proxy. 
					</para>
				</step>
			</substeps>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		You have created and configured a virtual machine pool with the specified number of identical virtual machines. You can view these virtual machines in the <guilabel>Virtual Machines</guilabel> resource tab, or in the details pane of the <guilabel>Pools</guilabel> resource tab; a virtual machine in a pool is distinguished from independent virtual machines by its icon.
	</para>
</section>
