<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Editing_VFs_on_NIC">
	<title>Editing the Virtual Function Configuration on a NIC</title>
	<para>
   Single Root I/O Virtualization (SR-IOV) enables a single PCIe endpoint to be used as multiple separate devices. This is achieved through the introduction of two PCIe functions: physical functions (PFs) and virtual functions (VFs). A PCIe card can have between one and eight PFs, but each PF can support many more VFs (dependent on the device).
	</para>
	<para>
		You can edit the configuration of SR-IOV-capable Network Interface Controllers (NICs) through the Red Hat Virtualization Manager, including the number of VFs on each NIC and to specify the virtual networks allowed to access the VFs.
	</para>
	<para>
		Once VFs have been created, each can be treated as a standalone NIC. This includes having one or more logical networks assigned to them, creating bonded interfaces with them, and to directly assign vNICs to them for direct device passthrough.
	</para>
	<para>
		A vNIC must have the passthrough property enabled in order to be directly attached to a VF. See <xref linkend="Marking_vNIC_as_Passthrough" />.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Editing the Virtual Function Configuration on a NIC</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select an SR-IOV-capable host and click the <guilabel>Network Interfaces</guilabel> tab in the details pane. 
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Setup Host Networks</guibutton> to open the <guilabel>Setup Host Networks</guilabel> window.

			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select an SR-IOV-capable NIC, marked with a <inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/SR-IOV-icon.png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>, and click the pencil icon to open the <guilabel>Edit Virtual Functions (SR-IOV) configuration of <replaceable>NIC</replaceable></guilabel> window.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				To edit the number of virtual functions, click the <guilabel>Number of VFs setting</guilabel> drop-down button and edit the <guilabel>Number of VFs</guilabel> text field. 
			</para>
		<important>
			<para>
				Changing the number of VFs will delete all previous VFs on the network interface before creating new VFs. This includes any VFs that have virtual machines directly attached. 
			</para>
		</important>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>All Networks</guilabel> check box is selected by default, allowing all networks to access the virtual functions. To specify the virtual networks allowed to access the virtual functions, select the <guilabel>Specific networks</guilabel> radio button to list all networks. You can then either select the check box for desired networks, or you can use the <guilabel>Labels</guilabel> text field to automatically select networks based on one or more network labels.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window. Note that the configuration changes will not take effect until you click the <guibutton>OK</guibutton> button in the <guilabel>Setup Host Networks</guilabel> window.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		
	</para>
</section>



