<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Explanation_of_Settings_in_the_VM_Interface_Profile_Window" remap="TID_25201">
	<title>Explanation of Settings in the VM Interface Profile Window</title>
	<table frame="all">
		<title>VM Interface Profile Window</title>
		<tgroup align="left" cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
			<colspec colname="c1" />
			<colspec colname="c2" />
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Field Name
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Description
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Network</guilabel>
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							A drop-down menu of the available networks to apply the vNIC profile.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Name</guilabel>
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The name of the vNIC profile. This must be a unique name with any combination of uppercase and lowercase letters, numbers, hyphens, and underscores between 1 and 50 characters.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Description</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							The description of the vNIC profile. This field is recommended but not mandatory.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>QoS</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							A drop-down menu of the available Network Quality of Service policies to apply to the vNIC profile. QoS policies regulate inbound and outbound network traffic of the vNIC.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>  
						<guilabel>Passthrough</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							A check box to toggle the passthrough property. Passthrough allows a vNIC to connect directly to a virtual function of a host NIC. The passthrough property cannot be edited if the vNIC profile is attached to a virtual machine. 
						</para>
						<para>
							Both QoS and port mirroring are disabled in the vNIC profile if passthrough is enabled. 
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Port Mirroring</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
                                                    A check box to toggle port mirroring. Port mirroring copies layer 3 network traffic on the logical network to a virtual interface on a virtual machine. It it not selected by default. For further details, see <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en/red-hat-virtualization/4.0/single/technical-reference/#Port_Mirroring">Port Mirroring</ulink> in the <citetitle>Technical Reference</citetitle>.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Device Custom Properties</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							A drop-down menu to select available custom properties to apply to the vNIC profile. Use the <guibutton>+</guibutton> and <guibutton>-</guibutton> buttons to add and remove properties respectively.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry> 
						<guilabel>Allow all users to use this Profile</guilabel>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							A check box to toggle the availability of the profile to all users in the environment. It is selected by default.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
</section>






