<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Importing_Networks" remap="TID_25160">
	<title>Importing Networks From External Providers</title>
	<para>
		To use networks from an external network provider (OpenStack Networking or any third-party provider that implements the OpenStack Neutron REST API), register the provider with the Manager. See <xref linkend="Adding_an_OpenStack_Network_Service_Neutron_for_Network_Provisioning"/> or <xref linkend="Adding_an_External_Network_Provider"/> for more information. Then, use the following procedure to import the networks provided by that provider into the Manager so the networks can be used by virtual machines.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Importing a Network From an External Provider</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Networks</guilabel> tab.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guibutton>Import</guibutton> button to open the <guilabel>Import Networks</guilabel> window.
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>The Import Networks Window</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/4995.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject> 
						<phrase>The Import Networks Window</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From the <guilabel>Network Provider</guilabel> drop-down list, select an external provider. The networks offered by that provider are automatically discovered and listed in the <guilabel>Provider Networks</guilabel> list.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Using the check boxes, select the networks to import in the <guilabel>Provider Networks</guilabel> list and click the down arrow to move those networks into the <guilabel>Networks to Import</guilabel> list.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				It is possible to customize the name of the network that you are importing. To customize the name, click on the network's name in the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> column, and change the text.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From the <guilabel>Data Center</guilabel> drop-down list, select the data center into which the networks will be imported.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Optionally, clear the <guilabel>Allow All</guilabel> check box for a network in the <guilabel>Networks to Import</guilabel> list to prevent that network from being available to all users.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guibutton>Import</guibutton> button.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		The selected networks are imported into the target data center and can be attached to virtual machines. See <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en/red-hat-virtualization/4.0/paged/virtual-machine-management-guide/52-network-interfaces">Adding a New Network Interface</ulink> in the <citetitle>Virtual Machine Management Guide</citetitle> for more information.
	</para>
</section>

