<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Increasing_iSCSI_or_FCP_Storage" remap="TID_42928">
	<title>Increasing iSCSI or FCP Storage</title>
	<para>
		There are multiple ways to increase iSCSI or FCP storage size:
		<itemizedlist>
          <listitem><para>Create a new storage domain with new LUNs and add it to an existing datacenter. See <xref linkend="Adding_iSCSI_Storage1" />.</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>Create new LUNs and add them to an existing storage domain.</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>Expand the storage domain by resizing the underlying LUNs.</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>		
	</para>
	<para>
       For information about creating, configuring, or resizing iSCSI storage on <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6</productname> systems, see <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux/6/html-single/Storage_Administration_Guide/index.html#iscsi-target-setup">Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 Storage Administration Guide</ulink>. For <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7</productname> systems, see <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux/7/html-single/Storage_Administration_Guide/index.html#osm-target-setup">Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 Storage Administration Guide</ulink>. 
   </para>
	<para>	
		The following procedure explains how to expand storage area network (SAN) storage by adding a new LUN to an existing storage domain.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Increasing an Existing iSCSI or FCP Storage Domain</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Create a new LUN on the SAN. 
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Storage</guilabel> resource tab and select an iSCSI or FCP domain.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guibutton>Edit</guibutton> button.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on <guilabel>Targets &gt; LUNs</guilabel>, and click the <guibutton>Discover Targets</guibutton> expansion button.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter the connection information for the storage server and click the <guibutton>Discover</guibutton> button to initiate the connection.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on <guilabel>LUNs &gt; Targets</guilabel> and select the check box of the newly available LUN.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to add the LUN to the selected storage domain.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		This will increase the storage domain by the size of the added LUN.
	</para>
	<para>When expanding the storage domain by resizing the underlying LUNs, the LUNs must also be refreshed in the Red Hat Virtualization Administration Portal.</para>
	<procedure>
	    <title>Refreshing the LUN Size</title>
	        <step>
	            <para>
				       Click the <guilabel>Storage</guilabel> resource tab and select an iSCSI or FCP domain.
			      </para>    
			  </step>
	        <step>
	            <para>
				       Click the <guibutton>Edit</guibutton> button.
			      </para>    
			  </step>
			  <step>
			      <para>
			          Click on <guilabel>LUNs &gt; Targets</guilabel>.
			      </para>
			  </step>
			  <step>
			      <para>
			          In the <guilabel>Additional Size</guilabel> column, click the <guibutton>Add <replaceable>Additional_Storage_Size</replaceable></guibutton> button of the LUN to refresh. 
			      </para>
           </step>
           <step>
			      <para>
				       Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to refresh the LUN to indicate the new storage size.
			      </para>
		     </step>
    </procedure>
</section>

