<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Managing_system_permissions_for_a_cluster" remap="TID_8758">
	<title>Managing System Permissions for a Cluster</title>
	<para>
		As the <guilabel>SuperUser</guilabel>, the system administrator manages all aspects of the Administration Portal. More specific administrative roles can be assigned to other users. These restricted administrator roles are useful for granting a user administrative privileges that limit them to a specific resource. For example, a <guilabel>DataCenterAdmin</guilabel> role has administrator privileges only for the assigned data center with the exception of the storage for that data center, and a <guilabel>ClusterAdmin</guilabel> has administrator privileges only for the assigned cluster.
	</para>
	<para>
		A cluster administrator is a system administration role for a specific data center only. This is useful in data centers with multiple clusters, where each cluster requires a system administrator. The <guilabel>ClusterAdmin</guilabel> role is a hierarchical model: a user assigned the cluster administrator role for a cluster can manage all objects in the cluster. Use the <guibutton>Configure</guibutton> button in the header bar to assign a cluster administrator for all clusters in the environment.
	</para>
	<para>
		The cluster administrator role permits the following actions: 
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Create and remove associated clusters.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Add and remove hosts, virtual machines, and pools associated with the cluster.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Edit user permissions for virtual machines associated with the cluster.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
	<note>
		<para>
			You can only assign roles and permissions to existing users.
		</para>
	</note>
	<para>
		You can also change the system administrator of a cluster by removing the existing system administrator and adding the new system administrator.
	</para>
</section>