<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Populating_the_ISO_Storage_Domain1" remap="TID_7637">
	<title>Populating the ISO Storage Domain</title>
	<para>
		An <acronym>ISO</acronym> storage domain is attached to a data center. <acronym>ISO</acronym> images must be uploaded to it. Red Hat Virtualization provides an <acronym>ISO</acronym> uploader tool that ensures that the images are uploaded into the correct directory path, with the correct user permissions.
	</para>
	<para>
		The creation of <acronym>ISO</acronym> images from physical media is not described in this document. It is assumed that you have access to the images required for your environment.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Populating the ISO Storage Domain</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Copy the required <acronym>ISO</acronym> image to a temporary directory on the system running Red Hat Virtualization Manager.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Log in to the system running Red Hat Virtualization Manager as the <systemitem class="username">root</systemitem> user.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Use the <command>engine-iso-uploader</command> command to upload the <acronym>ISO</acronym> image. This action will take some time. The amount of time varies depending on the size of the image being uploaded and available network bandwidth.
			</para>
			<example>
				<title><acronym>ISO</acronym> Uploader Usage</title>
				<para>
					In this example the <acronym>ISO</acronym> image <filename>RHEL6.iso</filename> is uploaded to the <acronym>ISO</acronym> domain called <literal>ISODomain</literal> using <acronym>NFS</acronym>. The command will prompt for an administrative user name and password. The user name must be provided in the form <replaceable>user name</replaceable>@<replaceable>domain</replaceable>.
				</para>
				<screen># <command>engine-iso-uploader <parameter>--iso-domain=<replaceable>ISODomain</replaceable></parameter> <parameter>upload</parameter> <parameter><replaceable>RHEL6.iso</replaceable></parameter></command></screen>
			</example>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		The <acronym>ISO</acronym> image is uploaded and appears in the <acronym>ISO</acronym> storage domain specified. It is also available in the list of available boot media when creating virtual machines in the data center to which the storage domain is attached.
	</para>
</section>

