<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization_User_Interface_Plugin_Discovery" remap="TID_14123">
	<title>Red Hat Virtualization User Interface Plug-in Discovery</title>
	<para>
		Creating plug-in descriptors is the first step in the plug-in discovery process. Plug-in descriptors contain important plug-in metadata and optional default plug-in-specific configurations.
	</para>
	<para>
		As part of handling administration portal HTML page requests (<command>HTTP GET</command>), User Interface plug-in infrastructure attempts to discover and load plug-in descriptors from your local file system. For each plug-in descriptor, the infrastructure also attempts to load corresponding plug-in user configurations used to override default plug-in-specific configurations (if any exist) and tweak plug-in runtime behavior. Plug-in user configuration is optional. After loading descriptors and corresponding user configuration files, oVirt Engine aggregates User Interface plug-in data and embeds it into the administration portal HTML page for runtime evaluation.
	</para>
	<para>
		By default, plug-in descriptors reside in <filename>$ENGINE_USR/ui-plug-ins</filename>, with a default mapping of <filename>ENGINE_USR=/usr/share/ovirt-engine</filename> as defined by oVirt Engine local configuration. Plug-in descriptors are expected to comply with JSON format specifications, but plug-in descriptors allow Java/C++ style comments (of both <literal>/*</literal> and <literal>//</literal> varieties) in addition to the JSON format specifications.
	</para>
	<para>
		By default, plug-in user configuration files reside in <filename>$ENGINE_ETC/ui-plug-ins</filename>, with a default mapping of <filename>ENGINE_ETC=/etc/ovirt-engine</filename> as defined by oVirt Engine local configuration. Plug-in user configuration files are expected to comply with same content format rules as plug-in descriptors.
	</para>
	<note>
		<para>
			Plug-in user configuration files generally follow the <filename>&lt;descriptorFileName&gt;-config.json</filename> naming convention.
		</para>
	</note>
</section>

