<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="User_Roles_Explained" remap="TID_11326">
	<title>User Roles Explained</title>
	<para>
		The table below describes basic user roles which confer permissions to access and configure virtual machines in the User Portal.
	</para>
	<table id="User_Roles_Basic">
		<title>Red Hat Virtualization User Roles - Basic</title>
		<tgroup cols="3">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Role
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Privileges
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Notes
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						UserRole
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can access and use virtual machines and pools.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can log in to the User Portal, use assigned virtual machines and pools, view virtual machine state and details.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						PowerUserRole
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can create and manage virtual machines and templates.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Apply this role to a user for the whole environment with the <guilabel>Configure</guilabel> window, or for specific data centers or clusters. For example, if a PowerUserRole is applied on a data center level, the PowerUser can create virtual machines and templates in the data center.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						UserVmManager
					</entry>
					<entry>
						System administrator of a virtual machine.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can manage virtual machines and create and use snapshots. A user who creates a virtual machine in the User Portal is automatically assigned the UserVmManager role on the machine.
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
	<para>
		The table below describes advanced user roles which allow you to do more fine tuning of permissions for resources in the User Portal.
	</para>
	<table id="User_Roles_Advanced">
		<title>Red Hat Virtualization User Roles - Advanced</title>
		<tgroup cols="3">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Role
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Privileges
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Notes
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						UserTemplateBasedVm
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Limited privileges to only use Templates.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can use templates to create virtual machines.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						DiskOperator
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Virtual disk user.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can use, view and edit virtual disks. Inherits permissions to use the virtual machine to which the virtual disk is attached.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						VmCreator
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can create virtual machines in the User Portal.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						This role is not applied to a specific virtual machine; apply this role to a user for the whole environment with the <guilabel>Configure</guilabel> window. Alternatively apply this role for specific data centers or clusters. When applying this role to a cluster, you must also apply the DiskCreator role on an entire data center, or on specific storage domains.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						TemplateCreator
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can create, edit, manage and remove virtual machine templates within assigned resources.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						This role is not applied to a specific template; apply this role to a user for the whole environment with the <guilabel>Configure</guilabel> window. Alternatively apply this role for specific data centers, clusters, or storage domains.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						DiskCreator
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can create, edit, manage and remove virtual machine disks within assigned clusters or data centers.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						This role is not applied to a specific virtual disk; apply this role to a user for the whole environment with the <guilabel>Configure</guilabel> window. Alternatively apply this role for specific data centers or storage domains.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						TemplateOwner
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can edit and delete the template, assign and manage user permissions for the template.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						This role is automatically assigned to the user who creates a template. Other users who do not have <guilabel>TemplateOwner</guilabel> permissions on a template cannot view or use the template.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						VnicProfileUser
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Logical network and network interface user for virtual machine and template.
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Can attach or detach network interfaces from specific logical networks.
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
</section>

