<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Administration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Using_the_Networks_Tab" remap="TID_14128">
	<title>Using the Networks Tab</title>
	<para>
		The <guilabel>Networks</guilabel> resource tab provides a central location for users to perform logical network-related operations and search for logical networks based on each network's property or association with other resources.
	</para>
	<para>
		All logical networks in the Red Hat Virtualization environment display in the results list of the <guilabel>Networks</guilabel> tab. The <guibutton>New</guibutton>, <guibutton>Edit</guibutton> and <guibutton>Remove</guibutton> buttons allow you to create, change the properties of, and delete logical networks within data centers.
	</para>
	<para>
		Click on each network name and use the <guilabel>Clusters</guilabel>, <guilabel>Hosts</guilabel>, <guilabel>Virtual Machines</guilabel>, <guilabel>Templates</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Permissions</guilabel> tabs in the details pane to perform functions including:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Attaching or detaching the networks to clusters and hosts
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Removing network interfaces from virtual machines and templates
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Adding and removing permissions for users to access and manage networks
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		These functions are also accessible through each individual resource tab.
	</para>
	<warning>
		<title>Warning</title>
		<para>
			Do not change networking in a data center or a cluster if any hosts are running as this risks making the host unreachable.
		</para>
	</warning>
	<important>
		<para>
			If you plan to use Red Hat Virtualization nodes to provide any services, remember that the services will stop if the Red Hat Virtualization environment stops operating.
		</para>
		<para>
			This applies to all services, but you should be especially aware of the hazards of running the following on Red Hat Virtualization:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Directory Services
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					DNS
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Storage
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</important>
</section>

