<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Introduction_to_the_User_Portal.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="The_Power_User_Portal_Graphical_Interface" remap="TID_12655">
	<title>Extended Tab Graphical Interface</title>
	<para>
		The <guilabel>Extended</guilabel> tab graphical interface enables you to access and monitor all the virtual resources that are available to you.
	</para>
	<figure id="desksym1">
		<title>The Extended Tab</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/6144.png" format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<table>
		<title>The Extended Tab</title>
		<tgroup cols="3">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Number
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Element Name
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Description
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						1
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Title Bar
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Includes the name of the <guilabel>User</guilabel> logged in to the portal and links to the <guilabel>Guide</guilabel> and <guilabel>About</guilabel> pages.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						2
					</entry>
					<entry>
						User Portal View Option Tabs
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Power Users have access to the <guilabel>Extended</guilabel> tab of the User Portal and the <guilabel>Basic</guilabel> tab of the User Portal. The <guilabel>Basic</guilabel> view is the default view for users with basic permissions.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						3
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Navigation Pane
					</entry>
					<entry>
						The Navigation Pane allows you to toggle between the Virtual Machines, Templates, and Resources tabs.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						4
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Management Bar
					</entry>
					<entry>
						The management bar is used to create and make changes to virtual machines.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						5
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Virtual Machine List
					</entry>
					<entry>
						The list of virtual machines, with the operating systems installed on them and their statuses (running, paused, or stopped).
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						6
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Virtual Machine Control Buttons
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Virtual Machine Control Buttons allow you to start, stop, pause, or power off virtual machines. 
						<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									<inlinemediaobject>
										<imageobject>
											<imagedata fileref="images/4646.png" format="PNG" />
										</imageobject>
									</inlinemediaobject> The green <guibutton>Run VM</guibutton> button starts up the virtual machine. It is available when the virtual machine is paused, stopped or powered off.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									<inlinemediaobject>
										<imageobject>
											<imagedata fileref="images/4647.png" format="PNG" />
										</imageobject>
									</inlinemediaobject> The red <guibutton>Shutdown VM</guibutton> button stops the virtual machine. It is available when the virtual machine is running.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									<inlinemediaobject>
										<imageobject>
											<imagedata fileref="images/4648.png" format="PNG" />
										</imageobject>
									</inlinemediaobject> The blue <guibutton>Suspend VM</guibutton> button temporarily halts the virtual machine. To restart it, press the green <guibutton>Run VM</guibutton> button.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									<inlinemediaobject>
										<imageobject>
											<imagedata fileref="images/5038.png" format="PNG" />
										</imageobject>
									</inlinemediaobject> The green <guibutton>Reboot VM</guibutton> button reboots the virtual machine. It is available when the virtual machine is running.
								</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						7
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Console Button
					</entry>
					<entry>
						The console button launches a SPICE window and connects to machines that have been powered-up.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						8
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Details Pane
					</entry>
					<entry>
						The Details Pane displays the statistics of the virtual machine selected in the Navigation Pane.
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table> 
	<!-- outpoint -->
	<itemizedlist>
		<title>Details Pane Tab Functions:</title>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>General</guilabel> tab displays basic software and hardware information of the virtual machine, including its name, operating system, display protocol and defined memory.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Network Interfaces</guilabel> tab displays the name, type and speed of the network connected to the virtual machine. You can add, edit and remove network interfaces using this tab.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Disks</guilabel> tab displays the name, size and format of the disk attached to the virtual machine. You can add, edit and remove virtual disks using this tab.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Snapshots</guilabel> tab displays a view of the virtual machine's operating system and applications. You can create and use snapshots using this tab.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Permissions</guilabel> tab displays the users and roles assigned to each virtual machine. You can assign and remove user permissions using this tab.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Events</guilabel> tab displays the description and time of events which affect the virtual machine.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Applications</guilabel> tab displays the applications which have been installed on the virtual machine.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Monitor</guilabel> tab displays the CPU Usage, Memory Usage, and Network Usage statistics for the machine selected in the Navigation Pane.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Sessions</guilabel> tab displays the Logged-In User, Console User, and Console Client IP for the machine selected in the Navigation Pane.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
</section>