<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Introduction_to_the_User_Portal.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Turning_on_a_virtual_machine" remap="TID_7380">
	<title>Turning on a Virtual Machine</title>
	<para>
		To use a virtual machine in the User Portal, you must turn it on and then connect to it. If a virtual machine is turned off, it is grayed out and displays <guilabel>Machine is Down</guilabel>.
	</para>
	<para>
		You can be assigned an individual virtual machine or assigned to one or more virtual machines that are part of a virtual machine pool. Virtual machines in a pool are all clones of a base template, and have the same operating system and installed applications.
	</para>
	<note>
		<para>
			When you take a virtual machine from a virtual machine pool, you are not guaranteed to receive the same virtual machine each time. However, if you configure console options for a VM taken from a virtual machine pool, those options are saved as the default for all virtual machines taken from that virtual machine pool.
		</para>
	</note>
	<procedure id="turn-on-vm-basic">
		<title>Turning on a Virtual Machine</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Turn on the standalone virtual machine or take a virtual machine from a pool as follows:
			</para>
			<stepalternatives>
				<step>
					<para>
						To turn on a standalone virtual machine, select the virtual machine icon and click the 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/4646.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> button.
					</para>
					<figure id="basic-machinedown">
						<title>Turn on virtual machine</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/5126.png" format="PNG" />
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						To take a virtual machine from a pool, select the virtual machine pool icon and click the 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/4646.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> button.
					</para>
					<figure id="basic-pool">
						<title>Take virtual machine from a pool</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/5132.png" format="PNG" />
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						If there is an available virtual machine in the pool, an icon for that virtual machine will appear in your list. The rest of this procedure then applies to that virtual machine. If you can take multiple virtual machines from a pool, the icon for the virtual machine pool will change into an icon for the last virtual machine you have taken when you take the maximum number of virtual machines possible for that pool.
					</para>
				</step>
			</stepalternatives>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				The virtual machine powers up. 
				<figure id="basic-powerup">
					<title>Virtual machine powering up</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/5129.png" format="PNG" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				When the virtual machine is powered up, the icon is no longer grayed out. The text displays as <guilabel>Machine is Ready</guilabel>. You are now ready to connect. 
				<figure id="basic-vmon">
					<title>Virtual machine turned on</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/5127.png" format="PNG" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<note>
		<title>Note</title>
		<para>
			You can only connect to a virtual machine after it has powered up.
		</para>
	</note>
</section>