<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Introduction_to_the_User_Portal.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="User_Portal_Graphical_Interface" remap="TID_8557">
	<title>Basic Tab Graphical Interface</title>
	<para>
		The <guilabel>Basic</guilabel> tab enables you to view and use all the virtual machines that are available to you. The screen consists of three areas: the title bar, a virtual machines area, and a details pane. A number of control buttons allow you to work with the virtual machines.
	</para>
	<figure id="basicdesksym">
		<title>The User Portal</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/6142.png" format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>
		The title bar (1) includes the name of the <guilabel>User</guilabel> logged in to the portal and links to the <guilabel>Guide</guilabel> and <guilabel>About</guilabel> pages.
	</para>
	<para>
		The virtual machines area displays the name of the virtual machines or virtual machine pools assigned (2). The logo of the virtual machine's operating system or a custom icon also displays (3). When a virtual machine is powered up, you can connect to it by double-clicking on the virtual machine's logo.
	</para>
	<para>
		On each virtual machine's icon, buttons allow you to start, stop, pause, or reboot a virtual machine (4).
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/4646.png" format="PNG" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> The green <guibutton>Run VM</guibutton> button starts up the virtual machine. It is available when the virtual machine is paused, stopped or powered off.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/4647.png" format="PNG" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> The red <guibutton>Shutdown VM</guibutton> button stops the virtual machine. It is available when the virtual machine is running.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/4648.png" format="PNG" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> The blue <guibutton>Suspend VM</guibutton> button temporarily halts the virtual machine. To restart it, press the green <guibutton>Run VM</guibutton> button.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/5038.png" format="PNG" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> The green <guibutton>Reboot VM</guibutton> button reboots the virtual machine. It is available when the virtual machine is running.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		The status of the virtual machine is indicated by the text below the virtual machine's icon - <guilabel>Machine is Ready</guilabel> or <guilabel>Machine is Down</guilabel>.
	</para>
	<para>
		Clicking on a virtual machine displays the statistics of the selected virtual machine on the details pane to the right (5), including the operating system, defined memory, number of cores and size of virtual drives. You can also configure connection protocol options (6) such as enabling the use of USB devices or local drives.
	</para>
</section>