<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE appendix PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<appendix id="appe-Changing_the_Permissions_for_the_Local_ISO_Domain">
	<title>Changing the Permissions for the Local ISO Domain</title> 
	<para>
		If the Manager was configured during setup to provide a local <acronym>ISO</acronym> domain, that domain can be attached to one or more data centers, and used to provide virtual machine image files. By default, the access control list (<acronym>ACL</acronym>) for the local <acronym>ISO</acronym> domain provides read and write access for only the Manager machine. Virtualization hosts require read and write access to the <acronym>ISO</acronym> domain in order to attach the domain to a data center. Use this procedure if network or host details were not available at the time of setup, or if you need to update the <acronym>ACL</acronym> at any time.
	</para>
	<para>
		While it is possible to allow read and write access to the entire network, it is recommended that you limit access to only those hosts and subnets that require it.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Changing the Permissions for the Local ISO Domain</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Log in to the Manager machine.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Edit the <filename>/etc/exports</filename> file, and add the hosts, or the subnets to which they belong, to the access control list:
			</para>
			<screen>/var/lib/exports/iso 10.1.2.0/255.255.255.0(rw) host01.example.com(rw) host02.example.com(rw)</screen>
			<para>
				The example above allows read and write access to a single /24 network and two specific hosts. <literal>/var/lib/exports/iso</literal> is the default file path for the <acronym>ISO</acronym> domain. See the <literal>exports(5)</literal> man page for further formatting options.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Apply the changes:
			</para>
			<screen># exportfs -ra</screen>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		Note that if you manually edit the <filename>/etc/exports</filename> file after running <command>engine-setup</command>, running <command>engine-cleanup</command> later will not undo the changes.
	</para>
</appendix>