<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="Adding_a_Hypervisor">
	<title>Adding a Host to the Red Hat Virtualization Manager</title>
	<para>
		Adding a host to your Red Hat Virtualization environment can take some time, as the following steps are completed by the platform: virtualization checks, installation of packages, creation of bridge, and a reboot of the host. Use the details pane to monitor the process as the host and the Manager establish a connection.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Adding a Host to the Red Hat Virtualization Manager</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				From the Administration Portal, click the <guilabel>Hosts</guilabel> resource tab.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>New</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Use the drop-down list to select the <guilabel>Data Center</guilabel> and <guilabel>Host Cluster</guilabel> for the new host.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> and the <guilabel>Address</guilabel> of the new host. The standard SSH port, port 22, is auto-filled in the <guilabel>SSH Port</guilabel> field.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select an authentication method to use for the Manager to access the host.
			</para>
			<stepalternatives>
				<step>
					<para>
						Enter the root user's password to use password authentication.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Alternatively, copy the key displayed in the <guilabel>SSH PublicKey</guilabel> field to <filename>/root/.ssh/authorized_keys</filename> on the host to use public key authentication.
					</para>
				</step>
			</stepalternatives>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guibutton>Advanced Parameters</guibutton> button to expand the advanced host settings.
			</para>
			<substeps>
				<step>
					<para>
						Optionally disable automatic firewall configuration.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Optionally disable use of JSON protocol.
					</para>
					<!--(Do we still need this?)note>
						<para>
							In Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization 3.5 and above, the communication model between the Manager and VDSM now uses JSON protocol, which reduces parsing time. As a result, the communication message format has changed from XML format to JSON format. Web requests have changed from synchronous HTTP requests to asynchronous TCP requests.
						</para>
					</note-->
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Optionally add a host SSH fingerprint to increase security. You can add it manually, or fetch it automatically.
					</para>
				</step>
			</substeps>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Optionally configure power management, where the host has a supported power management card. For information on power management configuration, see <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en/red-hat-virtualization/4.0/single/administration-guide/#Host_Power_Management_settings_explained">Host Power Management Settings Explained</ulink> in the <citetitle>Administration Guide</citetitle>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		The new host displays in the list of hosts with a status of <literal>Installing</literal>, and you can view the progress of the installation in the details pane. After a brief delay the host status changes to <guiicon>Up</guiicon>.
	</para>
</chapter>
<!-- The same content is also in the Admin guide. Ensure to update both places-->



